本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译创作
欢迎爱好者加入我们  www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：大米稀饭001  spriteNT   莫莫头上草
校对：小砂锅  后期：Dragon  监制：可乐嘻嘻
■
我奠定大地根基的时候  你在哪里呢
那时晨星一起歌唱  上帝的众子也都欢呼
引自约伯记
第三十八章 四、七两节
弟弟
Brother...
母亲
Mother...
是他们把我领到你们的门前
It was they who led me to your door.
扪心自问  生命之路有两条
A man's heart has heard two ways through life.
一条是顺从天性  随性而为
The way of nature.
或是风度高雅  严于律己
And the way of grace.
你要选择属于自己的路
You have to choose which one you'll follow.
要有风度就无法事事顺心
Grace doesn't try to please itself.
受到轻视  遗忘和厌恶时要泰然处之
It accepts being slighted, forgotten, disliked.
受到侮辱和中伤时要学会接受
It accepts insults and injuries.
天性则需要顺从  需要取悦
Nature only wants to please itself.
感谢上帝赐予我们食物...
Bless our lord this food...
天性悦万物
Get others to please it too.
爱和一成不变的服务...
...loving and faithful service...
万物顺天性
It likes to lord it over them.
保佑我们的孩子...
...Bless these boys...
方能创其独特之道
To have its own way.
痛苦可以信手拈来
It finds reasons to be unhappy.
不论周遭世界多么灿烂
When all the world is shining around it.
又或爱正在天地间微笑徜徉
And love is smiling through all things.
他们教育我们  崇尚高雅举止的人
They taught us, that no one who loves the way of grace,
结局都很美好
ever comes to a bad end.
无论发生何事
I will be true to you,
我都会向你敞开心房
whatever comes.
我的儿啊
My son.
我只想去死  去陪他
I just want to die. To be with him.
上帝把他接走了
He's in God's hands now.
他从未离开过上帝
He was in God's hands the whole time.
不是吗
Wasn't he?
我的家
My home.
我的上帝
My God.
我什么也不怕了
I shall fear no evil.
不怕了  因为你在这里陪着我
Fear no evil, for you are with me.
你得到了什么呢
What did you gain?
别离我太远  危险就在附近
Be not far from me, for trouble is near.
快走吧  我们没事儿
Go on now, we're alright.
我们没事儿
We're alright.
谢谢
Thank you.
你应该忘记他
Shouldn't have your memories of him.
你要变坚强
You have to be strong now, and...
听我说  痛苦总会过去
I know, the pain will, it will pass in time.
这可能
You know, it might seem,
并不容易  但确实是真理
hard, my saying that, but it's true.
我不想忘记
I don't want it to.
生活总要继续
Life goes on.
人总有一死
People pass along.
没有什么是永恒不变的
Nothing stays the same.
你还有另外两个儿子啊
You still got the other two.
上帝先给予后收回
The Lord gives and the Lord takes away.
这就是他的行事原则
That's the way he is.
该去治愈的伤口  他却往上撒盐
He sends flies to wounds...that he should heal.
我都没机会说  我有多对不起他
I never got a chance to tell him how sorry I was.
我甚至
I even...
无缘无故就揍他的脸
punched himself in the face for no reason.
你弹琴时  我就坐在你旁边
You sit next to me at the piano
他一翻琴谱  我就训斥他
and I criticized where he'd turned the pages.
我甚至觉得羞耻
I might even feel ashamed.
为什么呢
Why shame?
可怜的孩子  可怜的孩子
Poor boy. Poor boy.
你如何来到我的身边
How did you come to me?
以何种形状
In what shape?
戴着什么样的面具
What disguise?
我看到了我小时候
I see the child I was.
看到了我弟弟
I see my brother.
纯真
True.
善良
Kind.
他十九岁时死了
He died when he was 19.
再查查  这个和这个有问题
Just check, this one against this.
她想复合
She wants to get back together.
但是感情都没了  该说的话也说了
But, the chapter's closed, the story's been told.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
再试试
Experiment.
年轻的时候  事业是生活的全部
When you're young, it's all about your career.
我只是觉得自己...四处碰壁
I just feel like I'm...bumping into walls.
世界落入了无能之辈手中
The world's gone to the dogs,
人们变得贪婪  得寸进尺
people are greedy and keep getting worse.
我试图理解他们
I try to get into their hands.
爸  我刚才不该说那些话的  对不起  我...
Hey dad, I'm sorry I said what I said, I'm...
没错  我每天都会想起他
Yeah, I think about him every day.
我不该说那些话  对不起
I just shouldn't have said what I did, I'm sorry.
你觉得呢  我明白  我明白你那么做...
What are you thinking? I know, I know what you did...
只有两个人遭到了客户的否定...
And only two of those were turned down by client...
我是怎么失去你的
How did I lose you?
四处游荡
Wandered.
忘记了你
Forgot you.
来找我
Find me.
她是怎么熬过来的
How did she bear it?
母亲
Mother.
你觉得我虚伪吗
Was I false to you?
上帝啊
Lord...
为什么
Why?
你在哪里
Where were you?
你知道吗
Did you know?
对你来说我们是什么呢
Who are we to you?
回答我
Answer me.
我们向你哭诉
We cry to you.
我的灵魂
My soul.
我的儿子
My son.
你来听听啊
Hear us.
照亮我的生活吧
Light up my life.
我追寻着你
I search for you.
我的家
My home.
我的孩子
My child.
你通过她与我对话
You spoke to me through her.
你在天上与我交流
You spoke with me from the sky.
那些树
The trees.
在我还不知道我爱你
Before I knew I loved you,
在我信任你之前
believed in you.
你是何时触动了我的心弦
When did you first touch my heart?
...呼喊着口号  勇敢坚定的
...and manfully to fight under
抗击罪恶  抗击这个世界  抗击邪恶
his banner against sin, the world, and the devil.
跑
我们要请麦曼德先生来吃饭
We're having Mr. McMander over for dinner.
这句话里有两个d音
This is a double bidder right on in.
这是什么
What's this?
-两头短吻鳄  -两头短吻鳄
- Two alligators. - Two alligators.
-长颈鹿  -长颈鹿
- Kangaroo. - Kangaroo.
跳  跳  跳  跳
Jump. Jump. Jump. Jump.
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
别这样
Please.
我知道
I know.
不行  不行
No! No!
是我的
It's mine!
找到我啦
You found me!
等树长高你早就长大了
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.
一大片的蓝
Blue far.
你
You.
害怕吗
Are you afraid?
过来
Come here.
过来  到这儿来儿子
Come here. Alright, now come back here son,
离那远点儿  那是斯潘塞家的院子  知道吗
stay out of there. That's Spencer's yard, okay?
看见这条线了吗
You see this line?
别过了界  明白吗
Let's not cross it, you understand?
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
看见这条线了吗  看这儿  看
Do you see this line? Look it here. Look here.
好了  回来儿子  回来
Okay, now come back here son. Come on back.
我们离那儿远点儿
Let's stay out of there.
一天早上  兔奶奶说到  亲爱的
"Now, my dears," said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning,
你可以到外面或者巷子里玩儿啦
"You may go into the fields or down the lane."
不过别到麦克格雷戈先生的花园里去
"Don't go into Mr. Mcgregor's garden."
你爸爸在那儿出过事
"Your father had an accident there."
那就是上帝住的地方
That's where God lives.
晚安  我们五年后见
Goodnight, we'll see you in 5 years.
想吃蚱蜢吗
Want to eat a grasshopper?
找到啦  我找到老骨头了
I found it! I found this old bone!
是块石头吗
Oh, is that a rock?
不是
No.
感谢上帝赐予我们食物
Bless this food to our use.
献上我们的爱与一成不变的服务
As to your loving and faithful service.
请使我们铭记那些需要帮助的人
Make us remindful of those who are in need.
阿门
Amen.
请把黄油递过来好吗
Can you pass the butter, please?
请把黄油递过来好吗  先生
Can you pass the butter please sir.
先生
Sir.
-你们今天干什么了  -去了学校
- What did you do today? - We went to school.
之后呢
After that.
院子里呢
What about the yard?
把滑道按我说的收拾好了吗
Did you put the runners in like I asked?
是的
Yes.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
看起来可不像
Well, it didn't look like it.
是的
Yes.
里斯先生很喜欢杰克的书评
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report.
没人问你话  亲爱的
Nobody's asked sweetheart.
别老让我说
You know this.
巅峰之作
Crowns!
勃拉姆斯  第四交响曲  托斯卡尼尼指挥
-儿子  -先生
- Son. - Sir.
把我的打火机拿来
Reach me my lighter.
你是不是忘了什么啊
Haven't you forgotten something?
你爱你的父亲吗
Do you love your father?
爱  先生
Yes, sir.
他们出发去找大蟒蛇克尔
...and they went off to look for Kaa the Rock Python.
他们发现蟒蛇沐浴在下午的阳光中
They found him stretched out
趴在温暖的岩礁上
on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun,
欣赏着自己美丽的新外衣
admiring his beautiful new coat.
我们三个里面你最爱谁
Who do you love most?
一样爱
I love you all three the same.
给我们讲一个我们没听过的故事吧
Tell us a story from before we can remember.
你爸爸曾经开过一次飞机
He went for a ride in a plane once.
那是别人送他的毕业礼物
It was a graduation present.
母亲
Mother...
我有优点吗
Am I any good?
很勇敢
Brave.
韦科市  警察局  刑事法庭
谁身上都会发生吗
Can it happen to anyone?
没人谈论它
Nobody talks about it.
让我别跟爸爸顶嘴
Help me not to sass my dad.
让狗狗们别打架
Help me not to get dogs in fights.
让我学会感谢所拥有的一切
Help me be thankful for everything I've got.
你住在哪儿
Where do you live?
让我不再说谎
Help me not to tell lies.
你在看着我吗
Are you watching me?
我想知道你是谁
I want to know what you are.
我想看你所见
I want to see what you see.
到这来
Come here.
你就站在这
You're going to stand there and
把门轻轻关上  重复五十次
you're going to close this door quietly, 50 times.
数出来
Count it out.
3  4  5
3, 4, 5,
6  7  8
6, 7, 8
不能只抓着上面
You can't just take off the top.
得连根拔掉
You got to get them by the roots.
你们的母亲很天真
Your mother's naive.
要想出人头地得有非凡的意志
It takes fierce will to get ahead in this world.
如果你太善良  别人就会利用你
If you're good, people take advantage of you.
那些形形色色的高官
Every one of these top executives,
知道他们是怎么坐到那位子的吗
you know how they got where they are?
从河中间漂下去
Floated right down the middle of the river.
别让人说有什么是你办不到的
Don't let anyone tell you there's anything you can't do.
向我保证  别重蹈我的覆辙
Don't do like I did, promise me that.
我曾梦想成为一名伟大的音乐家
Dreamed of being a great musician.
却半途而废
I let myself get sidetracked.
如果你想有所成就  就要坚定不移
If you're looking for something to happen, that was it.
生活  就要活出精彩
Life, lived it.
约伯曾憧憬巢筑高树的人生
Job imagined he might build his nest on high.
他坚信自己行事光明磊落
That the integrity of his behavior
会远离不幸  得到善报
would protect him against misfortune.
他的朋友错误地认为
And his friends thought mistakenly
上帝之所以处罚他
that the Lord could only have punished
是因为他做了见不得人的事
him because secretly he had done something wrong.
但事实并非如此
But no.
不幸也会降临到好人身上
Misfortune befalls the good as well.
我们无法避免不幸
We can't protect ourselves against it.
保护不了我们的孩子
We can't protect our children.
不能对自己说  就算我不快乐
We can't say to ourselves, even if I'm not happy,
也要让孩子们开心
I'm going to make sure they are.
我们御风奔跑
We run before the wind,
以为风儿会一路相随
we think that it will carry us forever.
但它不会
It will not.
我们如云般消散
We vanish as a cloud,
如秋草般枯萎
we whither as the autumn grass.
如树般被连根拔起
And like a tree, are rooted up.
在宇宙的宏图中  是否存在着尔虞我诈
Is there some fraud in the scheme of the universe?
是否存在着长生不老
Is there nothing which is deathless?
是否有不朽般的存在
Nothing, which does not pass away?
我们不能停滞不动
We cannot stay where we are.
必须勇往直前
We must journey forth.
我们得找到比财富和命运更重要的东西
We must find that which is greater than fortune or fate.
除此之外  没什么能带来安宁
Nothing can bring us peace, but that.
理智与公正是否使人免受病痛的折磨
Is the body of the wise man or the just, exempt from any pain?
挣脱不安的困扰  远离残缺的遗憾
From any disquietude, from the deformity
残缺可能会使美丽因虚弱而凋谢
that might blight its beauty from the weakness,
使健康不再
that might destroy its health.
你相信上帝吗
Do you trust in God?
约伯也离上帝很近
Job too, was close to the Lord.
你的朋友  你的孩子  你的安全呢
Are your friends and children, your security?
在这世上
There is no hiding place
困扰无孔不入  无所不及
in all the world where trouble may not find you.
无人知晓悲伤会何时来敲门
No one knows when sorrow might visit his house,
约伯也不知道
any more than Job did.
在那刻  约伯被剥夺了一切
At the very moment everything was taken away from Job.
他知道  是上帝剥夺了这一切
He knew it was the Lord who had taken it away
往事一幕幕重现
Return from the passing shows of time
他以为那就是永恒
he thought that which is eternal.
他只看到上帝伸出
As he alone see God's hand,
那给予的双手
who sees that he gives.
也许他没意识到
Or does not also the one see God's hand,
那双手同样意味着收回
who sees that he takes away.
也许他只看到上帝
Or does he alone see God,
那慈善的面庞
who sees God turn his face towards him?
也许他没意识到
Does not also he see God,
那同样意味着拒绝
who sees God turn his back.
他是我朋友
He's a friend of mine.
在城里继承了笔房产
The one who's after real estate in town.
弗兰克·杰克逊
Frank Johnson.
理发师出身
Started out as a barber.
后来成就了番大事业
He built something, big.
你可能会觉得他是三位一体中的第四人
Now you'd think he was the fourth person of the Holy Trinity.
他们对自己的钱财闭口不谈
They never talk about their money.
饿着的都是不该挨饿的人
Wrong people go hungry.
死去的都是不应牺牲的人
Die.
幸福的都是不值得被爱的人
Wrong people get loved.
这是个急功近利的世界
The world lives by a trigger.
想成功  就别太善良
You want to succeed? You can't be too good.
小伙子  尝尝我的玉米面包
Hey there young fella, try my cornbread.
你们想来点黄油吗
Do y'all want some butter, do you?
来一磅面包怎样
How about a pound of bread?
这样站着  知道吗  快点
You'll like this right? Okay? Come on.
装出一副惨样
Act like you're in trouble,
你不想挨揍  你不想惹麻烦
you don't want to fight, you don't want any trouble.
一看到他眨眼  就上去痛扁他
The minute you see him blink, crack him!
懂了吗
Okay?
来吧  三局了
Okay, come on, three quarters.
防守  要懂防守  好吧
Cover, you're going to cover, right?
打这里  不错  再用力点  不错
Okay, here. Come on, nice, harder, nice.
右手不错  看看左手怎样
That's a good right, let's see your left.
这是最重要的事
This is the most important thing.
懂吗  就这样出拳  同时注意防守
Okay? You come in this way, keep your guard up.
打我  快点  打我  杰克  打我
Hit me, come on, hit me. Come on, Jack? Hit me.
打我  快点  快点
Hit me, come on, come on!
这里  打这里
Okay, here it is, hit me!
快点  儿子  快
Come on, son, come on!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
拍拍干净
Wipe yourself off.
左手  别把舌头伸出来  会被打爆的
Left! Don't leave your tongue out, you're going to lose it!
左  左  右  右
Left. Left. Right. Right.
左手  用力点
Left, harder.
用力  用力
Harder. Harder!
打我  打我  快点  儿子  打
Hit me, hit me. Come on, son, hit.
给我点颜色看看  让我看看你都学到了什么
Give me something, show me what you got.
快点  继续
Come on, go on.
吃饭吧
One meal.
下桌
Leave the table.
你也想下桌吗
You too?
-你想一直和我作对吗  -没有  先生
- You going to continue to defy me? - No, sir.
你打断我了  我还没说完
You're interrupting me, I wasn't done yet.
我说完了吗
Am I finished?
-说完了吗  -没有
- Am I? - No.
谢谢  陛下
Thank you, Your Majesty.
编造的故事
Makes up stories.
花哨的字眼
Fortunate words.
他说别把手撑到桌上
He says don't put your elbows on the table.
自己却那样做
He does.
辱骂人
Insults people.
一点也不关心人
Doesn't care.
我还记得你出生的日子
I remember when you were born.
他们不让我回家
They wouldn't let me come home.
海军长官必须在场指挥任务
Navy said an officer must be present for the laying of the cue.
我必须出海
I had to launch.
下一个词  火山
The next word is volcano.
下一个  插座
Next word is socket.
把你们的答案交换一下
Please pass your answers to each other.
现在给对方评分
We're going to grade each others' papers now.
别开小差
No interruptions, please.
快点  把铅笔拿出来
Come on, get your pencil out.
宝贝  天啊  宝贝
Sweetheart! Oh God, sweetheart!
我的宝贝
Honey!
格里斯之墓
死亡很痛苦吗
Was it bad?
你也会死吗
Will you die too?
妈妈  你还没那么老
You're not that old yet, mom.
你在哪儿
Where were you?
你就这样带走了一个男孩
You had a boy die.
世事无常吗
Would anything happen?
韦科市  滴滴涕
什么都看不见  什么都看不见
I can't see! I can't see!
我为什么要做个好人
Why should I be good?
你都不是好人
If you aren't.
谢谢
Thank you.
快到了
We're close.
为什么偏偏这里裸露着
Why's this bare here?
树下不长草
The grass won't grow under the tree.
-吉伯斯家树下却长草  -他们有个园丁
- It does at Kimbles. - They have a gardener.
他们有钱
They have money.
当然是继承来的
Of course he inherited it.
在把活干完之前
I don't want to hear one more word out of you,
我不想听见你说任何话
not until this is finished.
你种得太密了
You're cropping that too close.
你得留点水
You're going to have to keep that water.
托斯卡尼尼
Toskanini.
为了一首歌  他就重录了65次
Once recorded a piece 65 times.
你知道他完成时说了什么吗
You know what he said when he finished?
没有最好
It could be better.
好好想想
Think about it.
你爸爸我有二十七项专利
27 patents, your father has.
它代表着占有  占有想法
It means ownership, ownership of ideas.
得好好利用它们
You gotta sew them up.
-疯狂地去占有  -抱歉我语出不敬
- Get them by the nuts. - If you pardon my French.
做个有钱人
Be rich.
你能成为你想成为的人
You make yourself what you are.
你得掌握自己的命运
You have control of your own destiny.
别说我不行
Can't say I can't.
你看到我有麻烦
You see I'm having trouble.
我还没完蛋
I'm not done yet.
别说我不行
Can't say I can't.
他为什么要伤害我们
Why's he hurt us?
我们父亲
Our father?
-来吧  文斯  快来  -接住  接住
- Come on, Vince! Come on. - Get it, get it!
来亲你父亲一下
Give your father a kiss.
谎言
Lies.
-我不能  -你能帮我做件事吗
- I can't. - Will you do something for me?
你能保证按我说的做吗
Do you promise you'll do it?
什么都不要问
Without having to ask what it is?
只需相信你父亲的要求是对的
Just have the confidence in what your father asks of you is right?
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
在接下来的半小时里
In the next half hour, will you
除了要紧事  你能不能管好你的嘴
not speak unless you have something important to say?
你今天做了什么  我的小鹦鹉
What did you do today, my fine feathered friend?
坐椅子的前部
Sit on the front of your chair.
这种姿势最好  我在报纸上看到的
It's better for your posture. I read that in the paper.
这你是从莱德贝特先生那里买的吗
Did you actually buy this from Mr. Ledbetter?
别说话  点头就行  是还是不是
Don't explain, just nod, yes or no?
别出声响
Be quiet.
你刚说什么
What did you say?
求你了
Please.
别碰他
Leave him alone.
Leave him alone!
过来  过来
Come here! Come here!
站起来
Get up there!
你让我自己的孩子跟我作对
You turn my own kids against me.
你破坏了我做的一切
You undermine everything I do.
你觉得爽了吗
How do you like it?
停下来
Stop it!
别动
Stop.
-爸爸去哪了  -出海了
- Where's Dad? - He's gone on a trip.
抓住她  抓住她
Get her! Get her!
互相帮助
Help each other.
别使劲摔门
Do not slam that screen door!
爱每一个人
Love everyone.
每一片叶子
Every leaf.
每一束光线
Every ray of light.
我们的礼物
Our gift.
闭嘴
Shut up!
-小心  -小心
- Watch out! - Watch out!
-快走开  -快走
- Go. - Go!
不如把玻璃砸了
I say let's bust them.
找到一只青蛙
Found a frog!
把它绑到冲天炮下面
Lets go set it off in a sky rocket!
他逃走了
He's getting away!
退后  退后
Get back! Get back!
他是不是去月亮上了
Did he go to the moon?
-他去哪儿了  -在这里
- Where is he? - Here he is.
这是实验
It was an experiment!
为什么
Why?
别再那么干了
Never do it again.
你保证吗
Promise?
你要告诉爸爸吗
You want to tell dad?
他们只是想吓唬你
They're just trying to scare you.
你听好了
Keep your ear there.
她得吸取教训
Things she got to learn.
我也一样
I gotta know stuff too.
他们说你不敢试  他们可不怕
They say you can't try stuff? They do!
你有什么害怕的
What do you need be afraid of?
你在害怕  我看出来了
You're afraid. I see it.
就是这里  就是这里
Right here! Right here!
我不能告诉你
I can't talk to you.
别看着我
Don't look at me.
再见  故事
Au revoir, story.
再见  黎明
Au revoir, dawn.
放进来
Put it in there.
我信任你
I trust you.
-你累了吗  -不  我从来不会累
- You tired? - No. I never get tired.
-你今早就累了  -没有  我装的
- You did this morning. - No, I was just pretending.
-你说我是骗子吗  -不是
- You call me a liar? - No.
-我不想打架  -你是害怕吗
- I don't want to fight. - Afraid to?
不  我只是不想
No, I just don't want to.
-要我说你就是害怕  你说我是骗子吗  -不是
- If I was to say you're scared, would you call me a liar? - No.
你在害怕  对吧
You're scared, aren't you?
别玩了
Quit it.
过来
Come here!
不
No!
我不想听你发号施令
I don't want to do anything you tell me to.
我只想做我自己想做的事
I want to do what I want.
你知道什么  你让他骑在你头上
What do you know? You let him run all over you.
我要怎么回去
How do I get back?
他们在哪里
Where they are?
这个很重  你得用两只手来拎
This one is heavy, you're going to need two hands.
-小心点  你知道那是什么吗  -中文
- Careful now, you know what's that? - Chinese?
中文  没错  就是中文
That's Chinese, that's very good, yes, it is.
你们父亲周游了世界  一直到了中国
Your father went all around the world. All the way to China.
这是泛美航空公司的
That's Pan Am Airlines,
你们父亲坐的就是他们的航班
that's what your father flew on.
整个浴室都是不锈钢的
The entire bathroom was stainless steel.
甚至连洗脸盆都是
Even the wash basin.
我相信事情进行得很顺利
I feel confident the deal is going through.
没什么  别管了  我会告诉莫丽让她去死好了
Nothing, forget it. I'll tell Molly to go to hell.
那是从德国带回来的
That's from Germany.
看见那个了吗
See that?
把那个放下  儿子
Put that down, son.
泰勒能过来吗
Can Taylor come over?
这个家对你还不够好吗
Was your family not good enough for you?
还会像上次煮那么久吗
It's not going to take as long as last time?
要有嚼劲
Al dente.
这是主观观点  你知道有什么区别吗
It's a subjective point, you know the difference?
主观的就是说是你自己的见解
Subjective means it comes from your mind.
别人无法证明
It can't be proven by other people.
很高兴再见到你  走吧  小伙子们
It's good to see you again. Let's go, boys.
有些事你无能为力
There are things you can't do.
有些事我也无能为力
But there are things I can't do either.
你以后不要再叫我爸爸  你要叫我父亲
You're not to call me dad, you will call me father.
-但是...  -不要插话
- But... - Do not interrupt!
-但是你以前  -不要插话
- But you did... - Don't interrupt!
这是你的房子
It's your house.
你什么时候想要我滚我就得滚
You can kick me out whenever you want to.
你巴不得宰了我
You'd like to kill me.
爸爸
Dad.
他为什么会出生
Why was he born?
求你了  上帝  让他去死吧
Please, God, kill him.
让他去死
Let him die.
让他离开这个世界
Get him out of here.
她只爱我一个
She only loves me!
我主  请以圣宠保护你的这个孩子
Defend O'Lord this thy child with thy heavenly grace.
保佑他永受圣恩
That he may continue thine forever.
日渐成长  圣灵赐福
And daily increase in thy Holy Spirit more and more
直至他去到你永恒的国度  阿门
until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom, Amen.
我看见些东西
See something...
把手指头放上来
Put your finger over it.
那里
There.
来吧
Come on.
我无法从心所欲
What I want to do I can't do.
只能违心而行
I do what I hate.
你要是想打我就打吧
You can hit me if you want.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是我弟弟
You're my brother.
你给我看的是什么
What was it you showed me?
我不知道怎么罗列你的罪孽
I didn't know how to name you sin.
但是我会说就是你
But I'll say it was you.
你总是呼唤我
Always you were calling me.
我希望有人爱我  因为我很棒
I wanted to be loved because I was great.
一个大男人
A big man.
现在却一无所有
I am nothing.
看  我们周围的荣耀
Look, the glory around us.
树木和小鸟
Trees and birds.
我活在羞愧中
I lived in shame.
我蔑视一切  忽视了荣耀
I dishonored it all and didn't notice the glory.
我是个愚蠢的人
A foolish man.
他们要关闭工厂
They're closing the plant.
他们让我选择
They gave me a choice.
要么失去工作
No job.
要么去做没人愿意做的活
Or transfer to a job nobody wants.
父亲
Father.
我从未懈怠过一天工作
I never missed a day of work.
母亲
Mother.
周日按时缴税
Tithe every Sunday.
你们的思想我永远无法断然接受
Always you wrestle inside me.
也永远无法忘记
Always you will.
知道吗  杰克  我对你的希望不过是...
You know, Jack, all I ever wanted for you was...
变成一个成熟强大  能主掌自己命运的人
Make you strong and, grow up and be your own boss.
也许我对你太严格了
Maybe I've been tough on you.
对此我并不感到自豪
I'm not proud of that.
我跟你一样差劲
I'm as bad as you are.
我更像你  而不像妈妈
I'm more like you than her.
那是我一生的全部  其余则一片空白
It was about all I've done in life, otherwise I've drawn zilch.
你是我的一切  你是我想要的一切
You're all I have, you're all I want to have.
我亲爱的儿子
My sweet boy.
你要像个呆瓜一直在那站着吗
Are you just going to stand there like a bump on a log?
想要收获快乐  只有去爱
The only way to be happy is to love.
只有去爱
Unless you love,
你的生命才不会一晃而过
your life will flash by.
对他们好点
Do good to them.
奇迹
Wonder.
希望
Hope.
兄弟
Brother.
养育我们
Keep us.
指引我们
Guide us.
直到时间的尽头
To the end of time.
跟着我
Follow me.
我把他交付与你
I give him to you.
我把儿子交付与你
I give you my son.